ERCAN TEKOGLAN

Full Stack Java Developer

+1 (432) 553 84 47 ercantekoglan@gmail.com ercantekoglan.com linkedin.com/ercantekoglan

Pursuing to take part in Java-related projects and add new achievements to my career as a Junior Software Developer. My prior experiences have honed my teamwork and problem-solving & analytic skills in software development.

SKILLS

Java	 Thymeleaf 	 HTML5/ CSS3 	React	Maven
 Spring Boot 	 Hibernate 	 Bootstrap 	JSON	Postman
 Spring Security 	 MvSQL 	 JavaScript 	 Rest API 	 Git /GitHub

WORK EXPERIENCES

Managing Partner – Rabbit Wireless – Odessa, Texas

03/2020 - Present

- Developed a business web page with HTML, CSS, BootStrap, and JavaScript to reach customers efficiently.
- Optimized SEO keywords and meta descriptions on the company's website and social media.
- Increased sales by up to 60% by managing online marketing.
- Stabilized account control by adapting Microsoft Office tools and third-party APIs.

Agricultural Engineer - *Different Companies* – *Turkey*

10/2013 - 12/2018

- Effectively used GIS technologies for land mapping and surveying around 200.000 acres.
- Contributed to the development of the GIS software system as a domain expert of the Ministry of Agriculture.
- Developed an Early Warning Software System with SMS method in cherry growing regions.
- Consulted on sweet cherry orchards with up to 700 farmers and increased the yield average by 20%.

PROJECT EXPERIENCES

USA Farmers - GitHub Link / On Youtube

- Maven-based Java Full Stack web application, runs on Spring Boot. Provides CRUD functionalities for users.
- Application internally communicates with MySQL database via Hibernate using Fetch API.
- External HTTP requests made to <u>plantnutrition.io</u> via REST API calls for calculation operations.
- Security protocols ensured via Spring Security with encryption.
- UI developed with Thymeleaf template engine while incorporating Bootstrap and JavaScript.

Chat Application – GitHub Link

- In-browser Messaging application. This application runs on a Spring Boot backend with BootStrap frontend that uses Session Storage to save each user's profile which can text/message.
- Messages are stored in MySQL relational database. Uses JavaScript fetch API to send retrieve data.

Java-React Full Stack Todo App – <u>GitHub Link</u>

- Todo App is a React based project to help the user for better time management.
- Users can do all CRUD functionalities.
- At the backend side Java, Spring Framework and Hibernate technologies used with H2 database engine.

EDUCATION

Coders Campus – 22 Weeks Java Full Stack Bootcamp

11/2021 - 05/2022

A.A.S Computer Science - Midland College - Midland / TX

08/2019 - 08/2021

B.S. in Agricultural Engineering - 18 March University – Turkey

10/2007 - 06/2012